First few seconds were left blank intentionally to adjust for ambient noise.
Hi, Kshitij Dwivedi here, a computer science undergrad at Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi.
SRFP the Summer Research Fellowship program is organised by the three national Science Academies
namely Indian Academy of Sciences, Bengaluru, Indian National Science Academy, New Delhi and
The National Academy of Sciences, Prayagraj every year.
In this program, students/teachers are offered several two-month Summer Fellowships
to enable them to work with scientists associated with the three Academies.
Students and teachers from all universities and colleges affiliated to UGC/AICTE/MCI or
Accredited Institutions of State Universities can apply for these Fellowships.
This year in 2021, I have been selected under the SRF Program and assigned under a mentor
Dr. Sudarshan Iyengar, an Associate Professor at Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Ropar.
For this internship I have been tasked to learn the programming language python which is
one of the prominent languages these days due to its wide area applications in the field of
machine learning, data science, artificial intelligence, natural language processing and many more.
I know the basic constructs of python but not in depth.
So, the first task I have been assigned is to create a video introducing myself and
conversing a paragraph of text having myself as the speaker which I am doing right now.
After this video, I have to extract audio from it and then convert the audio into text.
In simpler words, a SPEECH TO TEXT based system like Siri, Google AI assistant etc.
Once done, I have to align this text with the video as subtitles to this video with the maximum accuracy possible.
This is my entire task.
We wrap up with the video now.
Thanks a lot for listening till here.