This video is for testing purposes only.
First few seconds were left blank intentionally to adjust for ambient noise.
Hi satish dwivedi hair.
Uk computer science undergrad at jamia millia islamia new delhi.
Srsp the summer research fellowship program.
Is organised by the three national science academy namely indian academy of sciences bengaluru indian national science academy new delhi.
The national academy of sciences prayagraj every year.
In this program students teachers are offered several 2 months summer fellowship.
To enable them to work with the scientist associated with the three academies.
Student and teachers from all universities and colleges.
Affiliated to ugc aicte mci.
Updated institutions of state universities.
Can apply for this fellowship.
This year in 2021 i have been selected under the srf program.
And assigned under the mental doctor sachin anger.
Associate professor at indian institute of technology iit ropar.
For this internship i have been tasked to learn the programming language python which is one of the prominent languages these days.
Wide area applications in the field of.
Machine learning data science artificial intelligence natural language processing and many more.
I know the basic constructs of python but not in depth.
So the first task i have been assigned to create a video introducing myself and converting a paragraph of text.
Having myself as the speaker which i am doing right now.
After this video i have to extract audio from it and then convert the audio into text.
In simple words a speech to text based system like siri google assistant at 17.
Once done i have to align text with the video and subtitles to this video is the maximum accuracy possible this is my entire task.
Video now thanks a lot for listening till here.