This video is for testing purposes only.
First few seconds were left blank intentionally
to adjust for ambient noise.
Hi, Kshitij Dwivedi here, a computer science undergrad
at Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi.
SRFP the Summer Research Fellowship program
is organised by the three national Science Academies
namely Indian Academy of Sciences, Bengaluru,
Indian National Science Academy, New Delhi and
The National Academy of Sciences, Prayagraj every year.
In this program, students/teachers are offered
several two-month Summer Fellowships
to enable them to work with scientists
associated with the three Academies.
Students and teachers from all universities and colleges
affiliated to UGC/AICTE/MCI or
Accredited Institutions of State Universities can
apply for these Fellowships.
This year in 2021, I have been selected under
the SRF Program and assigned under a mentor
Dr. Sudarshan Iyengar, an Associate Professor at
Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Ropar.
For this internship I have been tasked to
learn the programming language python
which is one of the prominent languages these days
due to its wide area applications in the field of
machine learning, data science, artificial intelligence,
natural language processing and many more.
I know the basic constructs of python but not in depth.
So, the first task I have been assigned is
to create a video introducing myself and
conversing a paragraph of text having
myself as the speaker which I am doing right now.
After this video, I have to extract audio from it
and then convert the audio into text.
In simpler words, a SPEECH TO TEXT based system
like Siri, Google AI assistant etc.
Once done, I have to align this text with the video
as subtitles to this video with the maximum accuracy possible.
This is my entire task.
We wrap up with the video now.
Thanks a lot for listening till here.